overdrive.in 2018-12-26

# Privacy Policy - Overdrive

**Our Commitment**

Overdrive is strongly committed to your right to privacy and to keeping your personal and financial information secure. To earn your trust and confidence in our commitment, we are fully disclosing our privacy practices. We encourage you to read our privacy statement to understand what types of personally identifiable information we collect and how we use this information.

**Information collected by _Overdrive_ and how it is used**

Overdrive only collects the necessary personally identifiable information in order to respond to your requests for our customized products and services. Personally identifiable information includes, but is not limited to, first and last name, physical address, e-mail address, phone number, birth date, and any other information that itself identifies or when tied to the above information, may identify you as a specific individual.

This website does not collect personally identifiable information about you except when you specifically and knowingly provide it. Overdrive and its service partners use your personally identifiable information to operate the sites and services and to inform you of new features, services, and products from Overdrive and its affiliates.

_Overdrive_ may also carefully select other companies to send you information about their products or services which are related to the site's service but are not necessary to its operation (an "Extended Service"). If Overdrive intends to use personally identifiable information for an Extended Service, the Overdrive site will provide you with the ability and requisite instructions to decline this service. You may also stop the delivery of informational or promotional mail from Overdrive by following the instructions on the mail.

_Overdrive_ may disclose personally identifiable information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to (i) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on the site or its owners; (ii) protect and defend the rights or property of the site-owners, the site or the users of Overdrive, and (iii) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Overdrive, the site, its owners, or the public.

**User/member interaction features**

Overdrive has many features that provide for users/members to disclose their identities and communicate with other users/members. Your use of such features and disclosure of any personal details (e.g. e-mail address) by you through these features are at your sole risk and Overdrive accepts no responsibility for the same. However, if your privacy has been intruded as a result of participating in such features, you could notify us by e-mail at [privacy@overdrive.co.in](mailto:privacy@overdrive.co.in)

By accessing the Company website or this Application or otherwise using the Services, you consent to collection, storage, and use of the personal information you provide (including any changes thereto as provided by you) for any of the services that we offer. The Company respects the privacy of the users of the Services and is committed to reasonably protect it in all respects. The information about the user as collected by the Company is:  
• information supplied by users  
• information automatically tracked while navigation  
•information collected from any other source (collectively referred to as Information)  
• Information, received and stored by the company

INFORMATION SUPPLIED BY USERS  
Registration data:  
When you register on the website, Application and for the Service, we ask that you provide basic contact Information such as your name, age, address, pin code, contact number, occupation, interests and email address etc. When you register using your other accounts like on Facebook, Twitter, Gmail etc. we shall retrieve Information from such account to continue to interact with you and to continue providing the Services.  
• Accounts - Used for managing multiple user accounts within the app and for Login purposes  
• Contacts - Used for accessing users Contact in order to share articles through the app  
• Phone - To read phone state and enable user notifications on users device. IMEI is being collected to uniquely identify every user  
• Camera - In order for the user to upload images and profile image of the User. Lets user use Camera inside of Overdrive  
• Microphone - To enable voice command related actions  
•Storage - To access files folders from inside the App  
• SMS - To send and receive verification messages

Subscription or paid service data:  
When you chose any subscription or paid service, we or our payment gateway provider may collect your purchase, address or billing information, including your credit card number and expiration date etc. However when you order using an in-app purchase option, same are handled by such platform providers. The subscriptions or paid Services may be on auto renewal mode unless cancelled. If at any point you do not wish to auto-renew your subscription, you may cancel your subscription before the end of the subscription term.

Accessing and updating personal information:  
When you use the Services from Overdrive (websites or any of its sub sites), we make good faith efforts to provide you, as and when requested by you, with access to your personal information and shall further ensure that any personal information or sensitive personal data or information found to be inaccurate or deficient shall be corrected or amended as feasible, subject to any requirement for such personal information or sensitive personal data or information to be retained by law or for legitimate business purposes.  
We ask individual users to identify themselves and the information requested to be accessed, corrected or removed before processing such requests, and we may decline to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive or systematic, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others, or would be extremely impractical (for instance, requests concerning information residing on backup tapes), or for which access is not otherwise required. In any case, where we provide information access and correction, we perform this service free of charge, except if doing so would require a disproportionate effort. Because of the way we maintain certain services, after you delete your information, residual copies may take a period of time before they are deleted from our active servers and may remain in our backup systems.

Information from other Sources:  
We may receive information about you from other sources, add it to our account information and treat it in accordance with this policy. If you provide information to the platform provider or other partner, whom we provide services, your account information and order information may be passed on to us. We may obtain updated contact information from third parties in order to correct our records and fulfil the Services or to communicate with you • Demographic and purchase information: We may reference other sources of demographic and other information in order to provide you with more targeted communications and promotions.

Links to 3rd party sites/ad servers:  
The Application may include links to other websites or applications. Such websites or applications are governed by their respective privacy policies, which are beyond our control. Once you leave our servers (you can tell where you are by checking the URL in the location bar on your browser), use of any information you provide is governed by the privacy policy of the operator of the application, you are visiting. That policy may differ from ours. If you cant find the privacy policy of any of these sites via a link from the applications homepage, you should contact the application owners directly for more information.

When we present information to our advertisers -- to help them understand our audience and confirm the value of advertising on our websites or Applications -- it is usually in the form of aggregated statistics on traffic to various pages / content within our websites or Applications. We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our websites or Applications. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number or other personally identifiable information) about your visits to this and other websites or application, in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. We do not provide any personally identifiable information to third party websites / advertisers / ad-servers without your consent.

Information use by the company:  
The Information as supplied by the users enables us to improve the Services and provide you the most user-friendly experience. In some cases/provision of certain service(s) or utility(ies), we may require your contact address as well. All required information is service dependent and the Company may use the above said user Information to, maintain, protect, and improve the Services (including advertising on the "Application") and for developing new services. We may also use your email address or other personally identifiable information to send commercial or marketing messages without your consent [with an option to subscribe / unsubscribe (where feasible)]. We may, however, use your email address without further consent for non-marketing or administrative purposes (such as notifying you of major changes, for customer service purposes, billing, etc.)

Any personally identifiable information provided by you will not be considered as sensitive if it is freely available and / or accessible in the public domain like any comments, messages, blogs, scribbles available on social platforms like facebook, twitter etc. Any posted/uploaded/conveyed/communicated by users on the public sections of the "Application" becomes published content and is not considered personally identifiable information subject to this Privacy Policy. In case you choose to decline to submit personally identifiable information on the Application, we may not be able to provide certain services on the Application to you. We will make reasonable efforts to notify you of the same at the time of opening your account. In any case, we will not be liable and or responsible for the denial of certain services to you for lack of you providing the necessary personal information. When you register with the Application or Services, we contact you from time to time about updating your personal information to provide the users such features that we believe may benefit / interest you.

**Other Websites**

The Overdrive site contains links to other websites. Overdrive is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites.

**Notify Us**

If at any time you believe that Overdrive or its users/members have not adhered to these principles, please notify _Overdrive_ by e-mail at [privacy@overdrive.co.in](mailto:privacy@overdrive.co.in) and we will use all commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and correct the problem.
